{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following mineral is involved in protein metabolism and oxidation reactions?", "opta": "Molybdenum", "optb": "Manganese", "optc": "Magnesium", "optd": "calcium", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following mineral deficiency may result into impaired growth and development, skin lesions and loss of appetite?", "opta": "Zinc", "optb": "Cobalt", "optc": "Iron", "optd": "Magnesium", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a function of iron?", "opta": "Oxygen transport", "optb": "Immune function", "optc": "Brain function", "optd": "Gene regulation", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Consumption of which nutrient leads to the multiplication of oral bacteria?", "opta": "Fat", "optb": "Carbohydrate", "optc": "Protein", "optd": "Fluoride", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Examples of goitrogenic foods are __________ and __________ .", "opta": "turnips and corn", "optb": "rutabagas and okra", "optc": "raw cabbage and turnips", "optd": "cassava and lettuce", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following carbohydrate is effective in promoting the calcium absorption?", "opta": "Lactose", "optb": "Maltose", "optc": "Sucrose", "optd": "Xylose", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What condition is caused by iodine deficiency during pregnancy and is characterized by stunted growth, deafness, and mental retardation?", "opta": "Cretinism", "optb": "Keshan disease", "optc": "Multiple sclerosis", "optd": "Crohn's disease", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Iodine is a part of thyroid hormone and is essential for the prevention of", "opta": "goiter", "optb": "osteoporosis", "optc": "muscle weakness", "optd": "diarrhea", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What transports copper from the intestinal cells to the liver?", "opta": "Ceruloplasmin", "optb": "Secretin", "optc": "Acrolein", "optd": "Albumin", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which group is most often affected with copper deficiency?", "opta": "Elderly woman", "optb": "Alcoholics", "optc": "Active toddlers with limited", "optd": "Preterm infants food variety", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the main source of natural fluoride?", "opta": "Mushrooms", "optb": "Potatoes", "optc": "Meat", "optd": "Water", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following mineral is involved in the enzyme -controlled energy yielding reactions of metabolism?", "opta": "Calcium", "optb": "Phosphorus", "optc": "Iron", "optd": "Copper", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The mineral which aids in the utilization of iron and in hemoglobin synthesis is", "opta": "calcium", "optb": "phosphorus", "optc": "cobalt", "optd": "copper", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The mineral which is considered important in maintaining electrical potential in nerves and membranes is", "opta": "magnesium", "optb": "manganese", "optc": "calcium", "optd": "iron", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Wilson's disease is an example of __________ and Menkes' syndrome is an example of __________ .", "opta": "zinc deficiency; zinc toxicity", "optb": "zinc toxicity; zinc deficiency", "optc": "copper deficiency; copper toxicity", "optd": "copper toxicity; copper deficiency", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct?", "opta": "Cobalt is part of vitamin B12.", "optb": "Cobalt will not replace the need for vitamin B12 in humans", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Cobalt will replace the need for vitamin B12 in humans", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is required as a component of blood hemoglobin?", "opta": "Iron", "optb": "Magnesium", "optc": "Calcium", "optd": "Copper", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Adding __________ to a breakfast of cereal will help your body absorb iron.", "opta": "milk", "optb": "orange juice", "optc": "coffee", "optd": "water", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following ion is required for the development of sound teeth with resistance to tooth decay?", "opta": "Fluoride ion", "optb": "Sodium ion", "optc": "Chloride ion", "optd": "Magnesium ion", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following two beverages contribute 20 to 30 percent of our daily manganese intake?", "opta": "Milk or tea", "optb": "Cola or coffee", "optc": "Tea or orange juice", "optd": "Milk or orange juice", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An endemic disease of cardiomyopathy in children is attributed to", "opta": "low Se in the environment", "optb": "low intake of iron", "optc": "high Se in the environment", "optd": "high intake of iron", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is correct?", "opta": "Sodium and chloride are the chief extracellular ions of the body", "optb": "Sodium and chloride are primarily involved in maintaining osmotic equilibrium and body fluid volume.", "optc": "Chloride ion is necessary for the production of hydrochloric acid of gastric juice.", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is necessary for the clotting of blood, functions of certain enzymes and control of fluids through cell membranes?", "opta": "Calcium", "optb": "Magnesium", "optc": "Copper", "optd": "Cobalt", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Selenium deficiency leads to", "opta": "liver necrosis", "optb": "diarrhea", "optc": "multiple sclerosis", "optd": "Crohn's disease", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Manganese is a key component of all of the following enzymes except", "opta": "arginase", "optb": "pyruvate carboxylase", "optc": "ceruloplasmin", "optd": "Mn-superoxide dismutase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following vitamin is essential for the absorption of calcium from the intestinal tract?", "opta": "Vitamin D", "optb": "Vitamin E", "optc": "Vitamin B12", "optd": "Vitamin B6", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which trace mineral is a component of the enzyme that activates vitamin A in the eye?", "opta": "Zinc", "optb": "Iron", "optc": "Iodine", "optd": "Chromium", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chronic consumption of excess selenium can lead to", "opta": "brittle hair and nails.", "optb": "muscle weakness,", "optc": "TPN", "optd": "diarrhea.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Normal glucose metabolism requires", "opta": "chromium", "optb": "manganese", "optc": "magnesium", "optd": "calcium", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Manganese is needed for", "opta": "normal bone structure", "optb": "reproduction and functioning of central nervous system", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "muscle strengthening", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}